Irena Grocka
Software QA Engineer
8 Gatekeeper Way
Worksop
S81 7SS
07716948239
Irena.Grocka@gmail.com

SUMMARY

As a Senior Test Analyst with extensive experience in software testing, I possess a logical and analytical mind that allows me to approach problem-solving with a practical mindset. With excellent communication skills, I have experience in supervising both in-house and third-party testing resources across all testing phases using both Waterfall and Agile methodologies.

Achievements:

- Successfully delivered nine projects as a Senior Quality Engineer at Pendo.io within timescales and budgets, with the first beta of the last project completed ahead of schedule and the regression pack automated at 85%.
- Exceeded the set goal of 100 customers signed up for the open beta threefold.
- Involved in the development and implementation of the release process for the Feedback pillar and the creation of automated regression and sanity using Cypress's end-to-end framework.
- Developed documentation of processes and good practices for quality, risk management, and automation as part of the Tiger team.
- Successfully delivered major programs on SAP upgrade and GK Retail EPOS System upgrades at Wilko's, providing benefits and savings to the company by working alongside and supervising both internal and third-party suppliers in all functional testing phases (System, System integration, UAT) to agreed timescales.

Skills Summary:

- ISEB/ISTQB Foundation Testing qualification
- Full Testing Life Cycle Experience
- Test Strategies and Test Plan creation
- Test Planning, Cases & Processes (TestRail, Quality Centre/ALM 11 and 12.5 Administrator)
- Defect Management
- Functional Testing
- Usability Testing
- Accessibility Testing
- API testing (Postman)
- Test Automation (Cypress)
- Agile methodologies

- STLC and SDLC methodology
- Process Definition
- Coordinating Code Releases in CircleCI
- Change Management (CHARM)
- GitHub/CircleCI/VS Code
- JIRA/Trello/Mirro
- UAT Test coordinator
- System Integration Testing
- Exploratory Testing
- Team/Slack

EXPERIENCE

Apply Digital

London - Quality Engineer

March 2023 - now

- Backend testing with Postman
- Backend contract testing using Pact Broker
- Implementing machine learning search engine Constructor.io for eCommerce customer.
- Test the microservices architecture in AWS
- Work towards customers' requirements to provide new website solutions.
- Creating the Pact Broker contract testing documentation with a working proof of concept.
- Evaluation, creation of documentation, and proof of concept of the available testing tools for the backend (Postman, Soap UI, Ready API, Rest Assured, PlayWright, Cypress).
- Creating the process for bug recording, triaging, and analytics.
- Creating the documentation for group testing.
- Creating the guidelines for testing payments.

Pendo.io.

Sheffield - Senior Quality Engineer

Feb 2022 -Mar 2023

- Provided extensive high-level testing advice to the feature team(s).
- Facilitated the team's testing work and mitigated risk via wide-reaching testing strategies.
- Understood and monitored interdependencies between product areas and ensured alignment between teams.
- Streamlined and improved quality processes.
- Monitored quality standards and key data.
- Conducted code reviews for automated tests and advised on the best practices of Cypress automation to junior engineers.
- Advised team on quality best practices.
- Created documentation for quality test practices and processes.
- Worked with stakeholders to design testing solutions that balanced technical and business needs and spanned multiple systems.

- Was an expert in one or more of the team's most critical systems.
- Was trusted by teammates and stakeholders to establish realistic complexity and/or delivery estimates that drove urgency but could be met while working in a healthy and mature way.
- Collaborated with team stakeholders to find the right balance between perfection and timeliness when testing technical solutions.
- Fostered clear, concise, effective, audience-oriented communication regarding work with teammates and stakeholders.
- Worked with stakeholders to identify and mitigate roadblocks and risks in the team's most impactful projects.

Pendo.io,

Sheffield - Quality Engineer

May 2020 – Jan 2022

- Independently executed manual and automated feature testing.
- Defined, verified, and executed manual release (sanity and regression) tests.
- Created and maintained automated sanity and regression test cases with Cypress.
- Debugged and resolved automation failures.
- Organized and led the execution of the team's releases.
- Identified and validated gaps in our testing and processes and acted accordingly to bridge these.
- Monitored customer-reported bugs and significant incidents and escalated/acted appropriately to remediation.
- Worked with the team and other stakeholders to understand and define customer needs.

Wilko,

Worksop - Senior Test Analyst

Jul 2019 – Apr 2020

- Provided technical testing support for both onshore and offshore test teams.
- Supervised a team of up to 10 testers, including test coverage, analyzing user stories, and providing support in reviewing test script creation and execution.
- Mentored junior test function members in testing.
- Provided technical expertise, support, and training in test processes and methodologies to agreed testing function standards.
- Worked closely with the test function manager in creating testing processes, including test strategies, test plans, defect life cycle procedures, and automation strategies, and reviewing testing requirements for all testing activities.
- Supported the maintenance of test methodologies for the IT department, defining test strategies and test plans for projects.
- Followed up on any outstanding open test risks/issues and managed the gathering of results for the project.
- Compiled test metrics for management using ALM11/12.5 and then reported to senior stakeholders on progress and issues.
- Identified and implemented a testing strategy for the company.

 Worked closely with testing partners in the creation of an automated test strategy and regression pack, identifying and prioritizing key business processes to automate and assisting in the creation of the automation scripts to build the Wilko Regression pack for SAP using UFT.

Wilko.

Worksop - Test Analyst Dec 2018 – Jul 2019

- Provided technical testing support for both onshore and offshore test teams.
- Supervised a team of up to 10 testers, including test coverage, analyzing user stories, and providing support in reviewing test script creation and execution.
- Mentored junior test function members in testing.
- Provided technical expertise, support, and training in test processes and methodologies to agreed testing function standards.
- Worked closely with the test function manager in creating testing processes, including test strategies, test plans, defect life cycle procedures, and automation strategies, and reviewing testing requirements for all testing activities.
- Supported the maintenance of test methodologies for the IT department, defining test strategies and test plans for projects.
- Followed up on any outstanding open test risks/issues and managed the gathering of results for the project.
- Compiled test metrics for management using ALM11/12.5 and then reported to senior stakeholders on progress and issues.
- Identified and implemented a testing strategy for the company.
- Worked closely with testing partners in the creation of an automated test strategy and regression pack, identifying and prioritizing key business processes to automate and assisting in the creation of the automation scripts to build the Wilko Regression pack for SAP using UFT

Wilko.

Worksop - Junior Test Analyst Apr 2017 – Dec 2018

Wilko,

Worksop - Promotion Data Coordinator Jun 2015 – Apr 2017

Linear Recruitment, Sheffield - Contract Worker Sep 2014 – Jun 2015

14th Highschool, Wroclaw - Part-Time Teacher 2009 – 2012 University of Wroclaw, Wroclaw - Teaching Assistant 2007 – 2012

EDUCATION

The University of Wroclaw - PhD studies in porphyrin synthesis 2007 - 2013
The University of Wroclaw - MSc General Chemistry – Distinction (Polish grade 5 out of 5) 2002
- 2007 The Technical University of Wroclaw - Study of Biotechnology 2006 - 2007

TRAINING

ISEB/ISTQB Foundation/Intermediate Certificate in Software Testing Trained and qualified chemistry teacher in Poland

SKILLS

- TestRail/ ALM 11/ 12.5
- Cypress
- GitHub
- CircleCI
- Google Cloud
- Postman
- Looker
- Sentry
- Mirro board
- JIRA/Trello
- Windows OS
- Mac OS
- G-Suit
- Microsoft Office
- UFT
- SAP HEC (On Hana)
- PO (Middleware)
- BW Data Warehouse
- SAP CAR (POSDTA)
- SAP S4 Hana with Fiori application
- CHARM (Change and Release Mgt)
- FileZilla
- DELPHI (Instore applications)
- GK Epos Systems
- UC4 Job scheduling tool
- SAP Finance

REFERENCES

References are available at your request.